<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://keepsweat.in/journal/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://keepsweat.in/journal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 07:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 07:38:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Mistakes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I released the first version SWEAT. on the TV app store I made a major mistake.  That mistake was compounded by the lack of discoverability on the TV at launch and looking back on it could have led to me missing out on twice the downloads.  That mistake was simply naming the app SWEAT. instead of something like it’s current name ‘SWEAT. - Workout and Exercise Routines’.  So on the surface that doesn’t seem like that big of a change but it starts feeling a bit bigger when you look at the search interface on the Apple TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/hecho/Sweat/website/images/journal/apple-tv-search-interface.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple TV Search Interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just looking at that image I think we can all agree that being in the top 10 for a given search term is much more valuable than not.  It’s the whole reason the most important news stories are above the fold, if you’re above the fold you have more visibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at the time that I decided I had a made a mistake and needed to update the name, I was the 17th result for ‘workout’ and the 12th result for ‘exercise’.  For ‘workout’ that puts me below the fold and for ‘exercise’ that basically puts me in the fold.  After my change (literally the day the update went out) SWEAT. was up to #9 when searching for ‘workout’ and #7 when searching for ‘exercise’.  That’s prime real estate, above the fold, and on a platform where Search is the discovery engine your rank in search can’t be understated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you or I learn from this tiny little mistake?  First, really think about the keywords that you’re using for your app (Are they relevant? Will people actually search for them?).  You can use a service like &lt;a href=&quot;http://sensortower.com&quot;&gt;Sensor Tower&lt;/a&gt; to hep figure out which keywords you should be targeting.  Second, don’t be afraid to include keywords in the name of your application.  Don’t overdo it and be ridiculous but sprinkling a few strategic keywords in the name of your app can have a very serious effect on your downloads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your left wanting to learn more about App Store Optimization, check out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://dancounsell.com/articles/what-is-app-store-optimisation&quot;&gt;blogpost&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://dancounsell.com/&quot;&gt;Dan Counsell&lt;/a&gt; or reach out to me on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/scottpetit&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 06:06:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://keepsweat.in/journal/app/store/2015/12/02/first-mistakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://keepsweat.in/journal/app/store/2015/12/02/first-mistakes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>App</category>
        
        <category>Store</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Working out isn’t easy.  Since I stopped playing sports in high school it’s become one of those things I know I should do but for one reason or another don’t.  The reasons are many and varying: I think I don’t have enough time, I’m intimidated by traditional gyms, I don’t see progress fast enough, I’m too tired, and so on and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I’m particularly unique in this feeling and you can probably relate to one or all of my reasons for not working out.  The thing is I no longer want to accept that.  I no longer want to feel like I don’t have time to work out, I no longer want to be forced to feel judged and intimidated by all the fit guys in the gym around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m building a business that solves those problems, not only for myself but for everybody else that’s not working out as much as they should.  That’s where &lt;a href=&quot;http://keepsweat.in&quot;&gt;SWEAT.&lt;/a&gt; comes in.  Right now it’s a simple Apple TV app that I built over the last 5 weeks but over time it’ll be all that you need to start sweating, one drop at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 16:26:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://keepsweat.in/journal/story/2015/11/20/introduction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://keepsweat.in/journal/story/2015/11/20/introduction.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>story</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
